All right. So, this is one of the harder
concepts to explain. So, I hope that
this explanation makes sense. What you
see behind me are a bunch of cupboards
and those cupboards store information.
What I would like you to do is I would
like you to imagine your computer and it
has a memory card. That memory card
stores information. So, this is all of
the storage information space on your
computer. So when you create a variable,
you are creating a variable inside of
that storage space. So here it's a
little off screen, but you can see we've
got our box. The box that I said is a
variable. So if we create a variable and
we put information into it, our computer
goes out to memory,
creates that box in memory and puts the
information inside of it. So if I bring
this out
and I pop it open,
I am storing my name as a string inside
of this box and my computer is storing
it out in memory. So when I need to
reference that variable, my computer
goes out to memory, opens up the box and
gets what's inside of it. I've also told
you that variables can take up different
sizes and space. Um, so you can have
numbers, you can have strings, and they
take up different amounts of space. So
what I've done is I've actually created
another variable here. In this variable,
um, I set it equal to an array. When I
did so, what it did is it didn't
actually put the array there. It created
a new variable in memory. And inside
that variable, it contained the text
that said, "Look next door."
So,
we close that variable.
It's telling me where I can find the
array. So, if I open up this cupboard,
and actually that is way off screen.
Tada. Here's our array that's holding
the actual information. The array is in
this cupboard. But when the computer
needs to access it, it first comes to
this cupboard and says, "Hey, where did
I put that array again?" And it says,
"Next door.
Where this becomes a problem is when you
want to copy the information in an
array. So if I want to copy the
information in an array, the array is
actually over here.
But my computer is looking over here.
So if I said create a second variable
and set it equal to
my array, what the computer does is it
comes to my array, opens it up, looks
inside of it,
makes a copy, and now in another folder,
we have the exact same message and says
look next door. So now
I have three variables in here. One of
them is storing a string and it's just
directly storing the information. The
other two are storing um what we call
pointers. They are telling me where my
array is located, but they're not
actually storing the array. The actual
array is still over in this cupboard
storing random information.
So when you copy arrays, you actually
have to go through some extra steps. And
this actually applies to the next thing
we're going to learn about which is
objects. But I wanted to talk about it
before we got into it.